sampathnirmalkumar@gmail.com

Objective:-

A challenging position as a Systems Administrator where I can deploy and use my technical, academic knowledge and experience in the best possible method.

Professional Profile:-

- Extensive experience in installation, administration and networking in various environments.
- Thorough knowledge of Windows 8.1; Windows 8; Windows-7; Windows XP; Server 2012R2;
 Server 2008; Windows Server 2003; Windows 2000 NT.
- DNS; A D Creation/Deletion; AD (GPO); WSUS; DHCP Policy.
- Excellent command of running projects employing industry standard project management techniques.
- Extensive documentation and training experience.
- Successful project and technical Project team Incharge.

Operating Systems: Windows 8.1; Windows 8; Windows 7; Windows XP.

Microsoft Servers: Server-2012R2; Windows Server 2008; Windows Server

2003; Microsoft Exchange 2003; MS Access 2003/2007.

Software: Symantec SEP-12.1.4.3; MSOffice-2013/2010; MSOffice-

2007/2003/XP; Open-Office; Outlook-2013/2010/2007; SAP; RAMCO; AutoDesk2013/2015; AutodeskVault2015 SolidWork2013/2014 and

Solid Work Vault2014;

Hardware: Intel, Dell M620; HP Proliant DL 380 G4; HP ProLiant ML 350 G4; Dell

Power Edge 2950;; Dell T9300 Workstation; HP Z200 Workstation, Dell PowerEdge M805; Cisco 1900 Series; HP 5900 Core Switch; Cisco 2960G; Cisco 3750; Fortinet 200D Firewall; D-Link – DES3200: Canon IR2230: Kyocera FS C-8520 / FS 1030 MFP; HP T1300PS

Plotter:

Virtualization: Microsoft Server 2012 - Hyper-V; VMware Workstation 10.

Networking: TCP/IP; V-LAN; VPN; IPMonitoring; Cisco Router configuration;

Switches; Namus Modem Configuration; ISDN configuration; installation and configuration of LAN, WAN and wireless networks.

Education:-

Bachelor of computer Application (BCA) Annamalai University - Chennai Diploma in Computer Science Engineering (DCSE) - Arani Hr.Sec Govt. Hr.Sec. - Ranipet SSLC - Ranipet

Company: Netaccess-India Limited (Murugappa group)

Professional Experience - 1 year

Wendt India Limited., (Murugappa group)

Designation: IT Support

- Responsible for Second-level (L2) support for all server related issues and more than 300 Desktop's and 70 Laptop's.
- Managing systems configuration and maintenance, problem troubleshooting, system and program security, applications and program management, planning and directing upgrades, and testing operations to ensure optimum system functionality.
- Managing SEP-12.1.4 Console; applying policies and managing users.
- Managing WSUS Server; Test and deploying the patches to clients every month as per policy.
- Monitored system and network activity to quickly detect any problems related to system security, performance, or system failures in a timely fashion and meet SLA agreements and provide daily technical support and 24/7 on-call support as well as weekend days.
- Monitor ticketing system for new tickets and work-items. Update existing tickets. Maintain hardware inventory control in ticketing system.
- Troubleshoot server hardware and software issues and escalate accordingly.
- Managing Network Printer: Plotter: Deskiet Printer:
- Installed and configured Migrated Exchange 2000 to 2003, Exchange client configuration using Microsoft Office Outlook.
- Installing and configuring SAP.
- Participated in complete system builds, upgrades, migrations, code deployments and patch management.
- Managing Users and Groups (Creation and Deletion) in Server2012 AD.
- Managing the Exchange Server2003, Mail Creation and Deletion.
- Administered change management related to server upgrades and software installation.
- Documentation of IT infrastructure policies, strategies & plan of action.

Proof of Concept (Windows Server 2012 Deployment)

- DC and ADC Migrated from Windows Server 2003 to Server 2012R2.
- DHCP and WSUS Server Migrated from Windows Server 2003 to Server 2012R2.
- Configured automatic updates for network clients by using Group Policy.
- Designed, planned and implemented Group Policy, delegation strategies and OU structure.
- Migrated Symantec End Point 12.1.4 and implemented security policies.
- Windows Server 2012R2 Hyper-V virtualization configuration for servers.
- Installed REDIUS Server for VPN user in server 2012R2
- Implemented FSSO (Fortinet single-sign on) for the Internet access.
- Implemented forti-Client for VPN.
- Configured the Mac Binding for all Server / Desktops / Laptop and Printer 300 devices
- Added and removed server roles and features; configured AD Domain Services roles; configured IIS8
- Group policies implementation for auto updating of windows client & servers using WSUS Server for user's domain.

Technical Environment – Windows 2012R2 Server; Hyper-V Server; Microsoft Exchange 2003; Windows Server 2008; Windows Server 2003:

Responsible for: Day-to-day support on Windows Server and backup/restoration for more than 20+ Dell /HP Physical Servers / 25 VM Machinesand monitoring the Data Center.

Company: HCL Info System Ltd.

Professional Experience – 3 years

Projects Worked:

- TNRSP (Tamilnadu Road Sector Project);
- TNSWAN (Tamilnadu State Wide Area Network);
- TATA Capital & Andhra Bank Project;

Designation: Customer Support Engineer

- PC installation and configuration, Computer Networking.
- CISCO router deployment and configuration, LL configuration, connectivity checking.
- CISCO switch configuration for TNSWAN project.
- Manage and maintenance of networking.
- System Configuration.
- ISDN Configuration.
- NOMUS Modem configuration.
- Handling for CISCO router and switches.
- Configuring and troubleshooting desktops, laptops and servers
- Troubleshooting hardware and software problems.
- Installing and configuring the peripherals, components and drivers.
- Installing software and application to user standards.
- Sound knowledge of digital and analog embedded computer hardware.
- Deep knowledge of printer and cartage refilling.
- Knowledge of motherboard and circuit designs of monitor.
- Proficient with electrical hardware test equipment (Multi meter, PCB testing card, analog meter, etc.)
- Solid understanding of all phases of SMPS and UPS
- Installed Hard disks, Floppy drives, CD Drives, Sound Blaster cards, CPU, Memory, Power supply unit, Network card, Video graphics card, Hard disk controller card on PC systems.
- Troubleshooting of personal computers. On line Support to customers concerning their computer problems
- Managing the Wireless Router, Switches and Modems.
- Configuring Managing and Marinating Networking Equipment's.
- Installing and configuring and administering technologies.
- Installing and configured DHCP Server.
- Backup and Data recovery.
- Virus Production (Norton, Avira,..)

Technical Environment – CISCO IOS, Windows XP, Windows Vista, Windows Server 2003, Windows Server 2008, Office 2010/2007; Open Office;

Responsible for:

- Day to day monitoring all the locations,
- Checking WAN connectivity.
- Router serial port checking and LL cable pair reliability.

Personal Details:-

Name	Nirmal Kumar.S
Father Name	Sampath T
Date of Birth	11-02-1988
Marital Status	Single
Nationality	Indian
Languages known	English, Tamil
Current Position	IT Support
Total Experience	3 Years
Level/Grade	L2 Support
Communication Address	6/12c West Cotton Bazar Street,
	Karai, Ranipet, Vellore- Dist.
	Tamil Nadu - 632 404
Declaration:-	
I hereby declare that all the information furnished above is true to the best if my knowledge	
and belief.	
	Yours Faithfully
Date:	Nirmal Kumar. S